Hanchun Lyu

Phone: 925-319-7819 Email: hclyuwk@gmail.com

SUMMARY:

Experienced web developer with developing dynamic web application using open source technologies, using JavaScript, Typescript, HTML5, CSS3, SASS and AngularJS.

Expertise on creating Responsive Web Design pages using Bourbon Neat to improve user experience when viewed on different size electronic devices.

Worked on web application in AngularJS and developing as a Single Page Application.

Experience working in agile methodologies to keep track of the ongoing project status and issues.

Using version control tools like git and svn to manage code version and releases.

Good team player and highly motivated self-starter with analytic, problem-solving, trouble-shooting, and debugging skills and strong multitasking ability.

TECHNICAL SKILLS:

Languages and UI techs

: JavaScript, Typescript, HTML5, CSS3, Sass

Web Development

: Angular JS, jQuery, Karma, Jasmine, Mocha, Chai, Bourbon-Neat, Bootstrap, NPM

AJAX, REST, Grunt

Version Control

: Git, Stash, Bitbucket, Sourcetree

Methodologies

: Scrum, Agile

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE:

Perficient, Inc. Aug 2015 - Present

Technical Consultant

Participated in a 7-10 person team doing front-end responsive web development for a healthcare organization's customer facing website. Multiple projects involved the use of latest web technologies, UI/UX design principles, and the integration of existing back-end systems with a RESTful APIs. The application's purpose is to provide customers an easy and intuitive way in managing their account and profile settings as well their billing information and notification settings. As a responsive web developer, the technologies used for the project include AngularJS, Bourbon-Neat and jQuery web frameworks for presentation. Data was retrieved through the use of AJAX requests to a single unified RESTful API. Other ancillary technologies included Grunt, Gulp, NPM, Bower, Jenkins, and Git.

Responsibilities:

- UI development from wireframes using HTML5, Sass, TypeScript, Bourbon-Neat, jQuery, and a style guide,
- Built an component based application using Google's AngularJS framework
- Created Services/Factories for reusable business logic
- Implemented AJAX Requests to create, read, update, and delete data from the back-end APIs
- Created end-to-end mock services that emulated back-end web services
- Developed easy to read code that could be interpreted and used by AEM developers
- Oversaw and managed the Jenkins project for building and deploying
- · Managed and maintained the Git-based Stash repository for version control
- Developed build tasks using Grunt or Gulp for pre-deployment readiness
- Utilized NPM and Bower for dependency management
- Ensured the application was fully functional on mobile device web browsers
- Documented functionality and implementations for future maintenance and improvements

FocusKPI Apr 2015 – Aug 2015

Web Application Developer

Participated in a four person team doing design, development, testing, and implementation of a web based application. The purpose of the application is to create a common outlet to present and visualize data, company news and events. As a Responsive Web Developer the project utilized AngularJS, Bootstrap, jQuery and web frameworks. In addition, data was transferred through AJAX requests to RESTful web micro-services.

Responsibilities:

- UI/UX design, creation, and implementation using HTML, CSS, Bootstrap, jQuery, etc.
- Created client-side authentication and authorization logic that persists throughout the browser session
- Built Controllers and Views to present and alter data Models for different functionalities of the application using AngularJS MVVW framework
- · Programmed Services that can be called by any Controller
- Implemented HTTP Requests to create, read, update, and delete data from the back-end database
- Created end-to-end mock services that emulated back-end web services
- Ensured the application was fully functional on mobile device web browsers
- Communicated with the web service developers and the product owner on expectations and requirements

Silicon Valley Imaging Oct 2013 - July 2014 RMA Technician

Maintained Company billing system and trouble-shoot data issues in holiday seasons.

Rebuilt new front end user interface for company website. Used Responsive web design to recreate grid layout for company products.

Responsibilities:

- Analyzed project processes and provide solutions of functional.
- Implemented solutions using system applications that increase efficiency and reduce risk through automation of manual processes.
- Designed the Web application layout and forms using HTML5, CSS3, and JavaScript.
- Worked on Browser Compatibility and tested each and every web application on popular web browsers such as Internet Explorer, Firefox, Safari, Opera and Chrome using browserstack.com
- Developed floating windows and the modal windows by using ¡Query.

EDUCATION:

Master of Computer Science, Northwestern Polytechnic University CA, USA Bachelor of Business Management, Zhejiang University, Hangzhou China

Jan 2013- Dec 2014 Sept 2006 -Jul 2010